Guide to the Tamiment Library Manuscript Files TAM.245
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Rocker, Rudolf: Four Letters, with donation letter from to Johanna Boetz, 1932-1956, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Roewer, George E.: Research Correspondence, Sep 12, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Rorty, James: "McCarthy and the Communists" (typescript), 1954 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Rosenberger, Ludwig: Correspondence (to Louis Lazarus), 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Rosny, Joseph Henry: Correspondence, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Ross, Arthur Leonard: Correspondence (incoming; includes Roger Baldwin), 1949-1968 (Box 6, Folder 31a)
- Rubel, Maxmilien: "Karl Marx et le Conseil Federal Anglais: Une Circulaire Inconnue" (French language typescript, 9 leaves), undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Russell, Bertrand: Correspondence (with Lucille Komisar), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Russell, Bertrand: Invitation to His 90th Birthday Dinner, Oxford (to Arthur Waley), 1962 (Box 6, Folder 33a)
- Russell, Charles Edward: Correspondence (outgoing; including Laura M. Caton, James Oneal, August Claessens, and Bertha Mailly to Mrs. Russell), 1913-1942 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Russell, Charles Edward: Speeches (typescripts), 1913 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Russia-Religious Freedom: Bibliography of Selected Publications Compiled by United States Department of State, 1918-1929 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Russian Émigré Intelligence Letters (Russian language), 1958 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Committee: Correspondence, Press Releases, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Sacco-Vanzetti National League: Correspondence, News Bulletins, 1928-1929 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Sacco-Vanzetti New Trial League: Correspondence, Jul 23, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Salt, Henry: Clippings, Correspondence (Catherine L. Salt, Samuel J. Looker, Laurence Housman, Sylvia Lloyd, Bertram Lloyd), Manuscripts, 1882-1957 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Sanford, Marvin: "A Contribution to a Bibliography of the Socialist-Communist Split" (typescript, 43 leaves), "Notes on the Cleveland Socialist" (typescript, 14 leaves), undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Sanger, Margaret: Letters to Gerald Swope (2), May 7, Oct 13 1934 (Box 6, Folder 42a)
- Sanial, Lucien: Letter to "Dear Comrade", Apr 20, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Saposs, David J.: "Short Outline of American Labor History" (typescript, 17 leaves), undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Saposs, David J.: "Self-Government and Freedom of Action in Isolated Industrial Communities" (typescript, 53 leaves), Feb 20, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Schapiro, Theodore: Biographical Information, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Schlueter, Hermann (Editor, New Yorker Volkszeitung): Correspondence (including W.J. Ghent, Sinclair Lewis), " Schlüter'sche Sammlung: Deutscher Sozialisticher Literatur" (typescript, 17 leaves, German language), Invitation and Ticket of Admission to International Socialist Conference, undated, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Schneiderman, Rose: Correspondence (to George Field), Apr 1, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Schuman, Mady Jan: "Let's Hear What the Red Boys Gotta Say!" (MA thesis, NYU), Oct 16, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Seger, Gerhart ( Neue Volkszeitung): Correspondence (from Erwin K. Schoettle), Mar 16, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Senior, Clarence: Letters to and from Socialist Party (Norman Thomas, Milen Dempster, James Oneal), 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Shannon, David A.: Correspondence (from Clarence Senior), 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Shannon, Theodore J.: "Worker's Education" (typescript, 5 leaves), May 3, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Shapiro, Theodore: Freedom of Information Act/Privacy Acts File, 1953-1965 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Shaplen, Joseph (City Desk, New York Times): Correspondence, Typescripts (some Russian language), 1935-1941 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Shaw, George Bernard: Letter to Harry W. Laidler; Letter to W. Simonson, Nov 2, 1915, Aug 20, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 56, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Sheridan, Clare: Correspondence, Mar 10, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Shiplacoff, Abraham I.: Correspondence, "To All Fair Minded Citizens of the East Side" (typescript, 3 leaves), 1923 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Shore, Samuel: "Labor and Political Action" (typescript, 5 leaves), "The Prince of Peace and the Lords of War" (typescript, 4 leaves), "Modern Machinery and Unemployment" (typescript, 4 leaves), 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Shub, David, and Vladimir Varsavsky: "The Men of October: Who Were They and What Became of Them?" (typescript, c. 40 leaves), undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Sifton, Paul: "Increasing Food Production to Win the War and the Peace" (typescript, 10 leaves), Jun 6, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Silone, Ignazio: "Daniel De Leon" (typescript, 19 leaves), 1918 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Sinclair, Upton: Two Letters to Miriam Collier Shipley; Clipping about, 1919, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Skidmore, Thomas: Research Correspondence (including James Oneal), 1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Slater, Louis: Correspondence (from Emma Goldman, Carlo Tresca, Dorothy Pearl, John Dos Passos, Michael A. Cohn), Manuscripts, Typescripts, 1931-1943 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Sobell, Morton: United States of America v. Morton Sobell, Memorandum in Support of Petition…, Feb 8, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Social Democratic Party of America: Correspondence (between Edward Bellamy and Cyrus F. Willard), 1897 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- South Slavonian Socialist Industry League: Declaration of Principles, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Sovereigns of Industry: Certificate, Dec 15, 1874 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschland: Leaflets (German language), undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Spargo, John: Correspondence (to W. T. Manning, Bertha Mailly), "The Socialist State" (typescript, 23 leaves); Autographed Menu, London, Sep 30, 1910 (signers include Walter Crane, H. H. Hyndman, Ben Tillett, Dora Montefiore), 1910, 1916-1919 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Spies for Peace: Pamphlet (photocopy), Apr 25, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Stamm, Thomas: Correspondence (to Bernard S. Cayne, Larry Lawson, Max Shachtman), 1946-1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Stampfer, Friederich: Interview Transcript, Mar 20, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Standard, William L.: "Merchant Seamen: a Short History of Their Struggles" (typescript, 250 leaves), undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Starr, Mark: Correspondence (from Laurence T. Hosie, Leon Rosser Land), 1938 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Starrett, Vincent: "Mexican Matinee" (typescript, 5 leaves), Mar 8, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Steffens, Lincoln: Letter to "Mr. Canby", Oct 13, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 21a)
- Stern, Fritz: "Finnish Impressions" (typescript, 4 leaves), 1940 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Stone, W.J. and Henry J. Taylor: "Kentucky Coal" (typescript, 39 leaves), undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Strobell, George H.: Testimonials (from Harry W. Laidler, Algernon Lee, Bertha H. Mailly, Upton Sinclair, Mary A. Sanford, Norman Thomas, Florence Kelley), 1925 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Struik, Dirk J: Life Story. Typed manuscript., circa 1969; 2013.031 (Box 7, Folder 65-67)
- Sugar, Maurice: Two letters to Abe Magil [1971-72]; Lyrics and music for the song "Fighting Inflation"; "The Detroit Song Book: Blood, sweat and tears from the 30s (Detroit: The Magazine of Michigan's Metropolis, July 23, 1967); "Feet of Clay" (Michigan State Bar Journal, May 1962), May 1962-Jan 28, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 24A)
- Suggestions re State Legislation against Injunctions in Labor Disputes, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Swinton, John: Clippings and Research Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Taft-Hartley Act: Statements and Press Releases (National Labor Relations Board, Congress of Industrial Organizations, ILGWU, TWUA, Steelworkers of America), 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Thouard, Jean: Letter to "Mon Cher Tom", 1/15/1977 (Box 7, Folder 27A)
- Tolstoy Foundation: By-Laws and Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Trachtenberg, Alexander: Correspondence (to Julia Stuart Poyntz), Oct 10, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Trager, Frank (Chair, Anti-Defamation League): Correspondence (incoming; includes George Edwards, Frank McCulloch, Felix S. Cohen, Sterling W. Brown, Wallace J. Campbell, Jerry Vorhees, David J. Saposs, Will Rogers, Jr., Carl Raushenbush), 1949 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Trades and Labor Conference: Labor's Demands of the Constitutional Convention(pamphlet), Feb 1, 1894 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Trotsky, Leon: Correspondence (outgoing; transcripts), Manuscripts (transcripts; includes "The Crisis in the American Party: An Open Letter in Reply to Comrade Leon Trotsky" by Max Shachtman); Letter from Houghton Library, 1937-1940, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Tucker, Benjamin: Correspondence (to Sidney H. Morse), 1873-1877 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Turitz, Helena: Correspondence (includes Solon De Leon, Scott Nearing, Algernon Lee, Daniel W. Hoan, Norman Thomas, Thomas M. Duncan), 1927-1928 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Tuvim, Abraham (Socialist Party) "To the Citizens of the 4th A.D." (typescript, 2 leaves), undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Twain, Mark: "The New Dynasty" (manuscript, 37 leaves, photocopy) and Associated Correspondence, undated, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Twentieth Century Fund: "Mutual Understanding" (typescript, 7 leaves), Apr 4, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Unemployed Citizens League: Forms, Minutes, "The Unemployed Fight for Themselves" (typescript, 7 leaves), 1933 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Unemployment Conference: Unemployment Insurance - Not Charity "Doles"(petition, signers include Algernon Lee), undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Union for Democratic Action: Correspondence (includes Sol Levitas, James Loeb, Frank Kingdon) Minutes, Reports, Statements, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- United Broad Silk Weavers Union (New York): Minutes, 1898-1899 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- United Labor League of America: Letter from John Pope Hodnett, President, to William E. Robinson, Mar 22, 1882 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- United Mine Workers of America: Correspondence, 1938, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- United States Department of Commerce and Labor, Bureau of Labor: Employment of Women and Children Surveys, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- United States Department of Commerce and Labor, Bureau of Labor: Night Work and Overtime of Women and Children Surveys, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- United World Federalists: Correspondence, Press Releases, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Van Kleeck, Mary: "The Moscow Trials - A Major Victory against International Fascist Aggression" (transcript of speech on radio station WEVD, 7 leaves), Mar 22, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Van Loon, Henrik Willem: Letter (outgoing), Jun 30, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Various Newspapers: National Intelligencer (Washington, D.C.), New York Daily Tribune (New York, NY), Yonkers Clarion (New York, NY), Aug 30, 1856; Oct 12, 1854; Oct 21, 1863 (Flat-file-folder 1)
- Walden, Daniel: Correspondence (Upton Sinclair, John Spargo, Anna Strunsky, Harry W. Laidler, Norman Thomas), 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Waldman, Louis: "Address Before a General Membership Meeting of Greater New York Socialist Party, Dec 1, 1932" (typescript, 17 leaves), "The National Industrial Recovery Act" (typescript, 35 leaves), Press Releases, 1932-1934 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Wallace, Henry A. "Wallace Answers Truman" (transcript of radio address, 6 leaves), Mar 19, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Walling, William English: Meeting Notice (with Anna Strunsky Walling, Clarence Darrow and Peter Sissman), undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Wanhope, Joshua: "Report of Debate at Convention Hall, Rochester, N.Y. on Sunday, January 24, 1914, at 8 P.M. Between Mr. Joshua Wanhope and Mr. Peter Collins" (typescript, 47 leaves), Jan 24, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Ward, Harry F.: Address (typescript, 8 leaves), undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
- War Resister's League: Correspondence (from David McReynolds), 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Warren: Letter to "Arthur" re: Don Marquis, Nov 7, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Wayland, J.A.: Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Weekly People: Letter Box Answers (transcript of newspaper column, 1 leaf), 1909 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Weinstone, William: Correspondence (to Gus Hall), "Peaceful Coexistence and the United Front" (from Daily World Magazine), 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Wende, Edward: Letter to E.M. Martin (German language), Jul 18, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Western Federation of Miners: Correspondence from John M. O'Neill, Adolph F. Germer, William D. "Big Bill" Haywood, James Kirwan, 1905-1913 (Box 7, Folder 59)
- White, Bouck: Letter to "Dear Comrade", Jan 20, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 60)
- White, John P. (United Mine Workers of America): Correspondence (to James Oneal), May 11, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 61)
- White, Walter: Correspondence (to George Field), Mar 27, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Wilkerson, Doxey: "The Origin and Historical Background of the Negro Problem" (typescript, 7 leaves), Dec 11, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 63)
- William, Maurice: "The Future of Asia" (typescript, 6 leaves), undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
- Window Glass Cutters League of America: Correspondence (to Louise Heinze), Dec 2, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Winitsky, Harry M.: Correspondence, "Justice" (play script), "The Rights of the Horse and the Rights of the Man" (typescript, 4 pages), The People of the State of New York v. Harry M. Winitsky, Memorandum on Application for a Certificate of Reasonable Doubt, 1919-1922 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Winter, Helen: Letter to Oscar Ameringer, May 7, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Wisotsky, Abraham: Contacts (Business Cards), Correspondence (includes Alfred J. Mascia, Philip Dorf, Daniel W. Hoan, Winston Dancis, Lydia Avery), Election Materials, 1933-1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Wisotsky, Abraham: "The Ethics and Principles of Unionism" (typescript, 37 leaves), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Wolfe, Bertram D.: Correspondence (to Louise Heinze), undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Woll, Matthew: Telegram (to David Dubinsky), Feb 16, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Work Peoples College: Correspondence (to Nathan Fine), Dec 1929 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Workers Education Bureau of America: Convention Report, Apr 1925 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Workers World: Letter to "Dear Friend Rod", Apr 17, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Workmen's Educational Association Labor Temple: Letter to the General Committee, Socialist Party, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Young Communist League of America: "A Modern Socialism" (typescript, 57 pages, by Joe Mandelson, Sam Lehrer and Dr. Don Weissman), 1938 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Young Peoples Socialist Federation: Letter to the Executive Committee, Socialist Party, Oct 4, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Young Socialist Alliance, Baltimore: Notes for Talk on Lenin's "Imperialism" by Roberta Speel, Apr 28, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Zapata, Emiliano: "Manifiesto al Pueblo Mexicano" (typed proclamation, Spanish language; photocopy, original in vault), Apr 25, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 15, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Zucker, Abraham: Correspondence (from Algernon Lee, Adolph Held), Clippings, Scrapbook, 1913-1932 (Box 8, Folder 16)